Contact

steffen.lewis@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/steffenlewis (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

Customer Service

Certifications

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

Cardiac Surgery (Adult) (CSC)

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Cardiac Medicine (Adult) (CMC)

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

Steffen Lewis, BSN, RN, CCRN-CMC-CSC

CVICU Registered Nurse

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

A compassionate, vigilant, and resilient Registered Nurse whose adaptability allows seamless progression into diverse, high acuity patient care settings. A blazing desire to seek and certify knowledge, along with over five years of experience, has cultivated a premiere nursing professional focused on delivering quality service to critically ill patients and their families. Destined to enhance the nursing profession at the highest levels, the acceptance to pursue a Doctor of Nursing Practice with a specialization in Nurse Anesthesia is in development.

Experience

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions Per Diem Registered Nurse March 2020 - Present (3 months) Plano, Texas, United States

Medical City Plano, Plano, TX

513 Bed Level 1 Trauma, Magnet Teaching Facility, Comprehensive Stroke Center, Burn Center

10 Bed TSICU, 18 Bed CCU, 8 Bed BICU, 34 Bed NSICU

San Ramon Regional Medical Ctr Per Diem Registered Nurse October 2019 - Present (8 months) San Ramon, California

123 Bed acute-care hospital12 Bed ICU/CCU, ER, TELE

FlexCare Medical Staffing
Travel Registered Nurse
July 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 6 months)
Stockton, California

July 2019 - December 2019

January 2019 - May 2019

St. Joseph's Medical Center

355 Bed teaching hospital

10 Bed CVICU, 10 Bed RMICU, 10 BedCCU, 12 Bed PVICU

July 2018 - September 2018
San Ramon Regional Medical Center
123 Bed acute-care hospital
12 Bed ICU/CCU

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions
Travel Registered Nurse
December 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 1 month)
Plano, Texas

October 2018 - December 2018

Medical City Plano, Plano, TX

513 Bed Level 1 Trauma, Magnet Teaching Facility, Comprehensive Stroke
Center, Burn Center

10 Bed TSICU, 18 Bed CCU, 8 Bed BICU, 34 Bed NSICU

Dec 2017 - June 2018

Medical City Fort Worth, Fort Worth, TX

320 Bed Magnet Teaching Facility, Joint Commission Chest Pain Center,

Comprehensive Stroke Center

16 bed MICU, 8 bed NICU, 8 bed CVICU

Aureus Medical Group
Travel Registered Nurse
February 2017 - December 2017 (11 months)
Austin, Texas

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017 Saint David's South Austin Medical Center, Austin, TX 316 Bed Level II Trauma Center 8 bed CVICU, 10 bed STICU, 14 bed MSICU

Feb 2017 - May 2017 Research Medical Center, Kansas City, MO 590 Bed Level I Trauma Center, Comprehensive Stroke Center, Teaching Facility32 bed MSICU

Saint Luke's Health System
Staff Registered Nurse
June 2016 - August 2017 (1 year 3 months)
Kansas City, Missouri

Saint Luke's Mid America Heart Institute offers the most comprehensive care in Kansas City. We are the only regional facility providing the full range of cardiovascular services, from prevention to heart transplantation.

As a level I, Magnet Designated* facility, we are the #1 heart care providers in Kansas City. In addition, U.S. News & World ranks us 20th Nationally for Cardiology and Heart Surgery.

Staff nurse that demonstrates highly advanced skills in patient assessment/intervention, teamwork, assertiveness and crisis management.

Delivers high quality patient-focused health care services that meet the assessed and individually planned needs and desires of all patients and their families who are recovering from various cardiovascular/thoracic surgical procedures.

Our Lady of the Lake
2 years 2 months

ICU Nurse Resident
April 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 2 months)
Baton Rouge, Louisiana

As a new graduate RN, I completed an initial 24 week ICU nurse residency program at this level II, Magnet designated teaching facility. Complete foundational exposure totaled over 2200+ hours of bedside care with patients in various Adult Critical Care units; SICU, TNCC, MICU, Universal Cardiac ICU.

Demonstrated highly advanced skills in patient assessment/intervention, teamwork, assertiveness and crisis management.

Delivered high quality patient-focused health care services that meet the assessed and individually planned needs and desires of all patients and their families who suffer from various health deviations.

Universal Cardiac ICU (24 bed): Provided cardiac progressive care to patients with a variety of diagnoses, including coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction, angina and arrhythmias. Post-operative care is provided to patients that have undergone open heart surgery, heart catheterization/angioplasty, stents, and placement of pacemakers and defibrillators.

Surgical ICU (24 bed): Provided care for critically ill adult patients who are recovering from General surgical services provided by various surgeon groups (Neuro, GI, ENT, Vascular, Ortho, OMFS).

Trauma-Neuro CC (12 bed): Provided care for patients who have been involved in multi-system trauma, requiring specialized neurological surgeries and interventions.

Medical ICU (24 bed): Provided care for critically ill patients, common diagnoses include multi-system failure, liver failure, GI bleed, sepsis, respiratory failure (especially those with COPD exacerbation, asthma, and pneumonia), infectious diseases, diabetic ketoacidosis, post cardiac and respiratory arrests, and cancer.

Medical ICU Nurse Tech April 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 1 month) Baton Rouge, Louisiana

Performed various patient care activities and related nonprofessional services necessary in caring for the personal needs and comfort of patients. Also assists with patient bathing, feeding, and preparation for treatment, assessing and recording vital signs, changing bed linen, preparing treatment trays and other supplies, and assisted nursing service personnel with a variety of other patient care duties that I have verified competencies in. Relied on establish guidelines to accomplish tasks, while working under close supervision of the nurse.

Proven personal competencies with but not limited to: initiating IVs, NG tubes, OG tubes, Foley catheters, hemodynamic monitoring, external ventricular drains/ICP monitoring, trach care/suctioning, Oral/IV medication administration.

Also assisting assisting Physicians with bedside procedures such as but not limited to: insertion of central/picc/vas cath lines, upper and lower GI scopes, Bronchoscopy.

Thorough exposure to caring for patients experiencing health deviations such as DKA, Sepsis, CHF exacerbations, acute MI, GI bleeds, ARDS, Hypertensive Crisis.

Education

University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Nurse Anesthesiology · (2020 - 2023)

Southern University and A&M College- Baton Rouge Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing, 3.17 · (2010 - 2014)